'Kids these days, eh?' Three simple words that try to summarise many a misunderstanding across a generational divide.
“如今的孩子啊，唉？”这三个简单的词，试图概括代际鸿沟中的种种误解。
On one side, the older generation – stuffy, antiquated, and oppressive.
一边是老一辈——古板、陈旧、专断。
On the other, the younger generation – rebellious, ignorant and disobedient, and lacking in self-control.
另一边是年轻人——叛逆、无知、不听话，还缺乏自制力。
Or at least that's what popular stereotypes would have us believe.
至少，这是普遍的刻板印象想让我们相信的。
That said, every generation is different in one way or another to the next.
话虽如此，每一代人在某些方面都与下一代有所不同。
But if recent figures are anything to go by, juveniles may actually be improving upon their elders' behaviour.
但从最近的数据来看，青少年的行为实际上可能比长辈们更好。
British 16–24 year olds are drinking less alcohol and smoking less, according to a recent report from the UK Office for National Statistics.
英国国家统计局最近的一份报告显示，16至24岁的英国人饮酒和吸烟的次数都在减少。
From 2005 to 2017 the number of British adolescents and young adults who had drunk alcohol the week prior to being interviewed declined from 60% to 50%.
2005年至2017年间，接受采访前一周喝过酒的英国青少年和年轻人比例从60%下降到50%。
This is mirrored by their consumption of cigarettes, which dropped from 28.5% to 19.9% for the same period.
香烟消费情况也呈现出同样的趋势，同期吸烟人数比例从28.5%降至19.9%。
One possible reason for this youth's sagacity could lie in the cultural shift away from these behaviours – something they can thank their forebears for.
年轻人这种明智之举的一个可能原因是文化观念的转变——人们不再推崇这些行为，这一点他们得感谢先辈们。
Campaigns and adverts on the dangers of smoking and drinking have been persevering.
关于吸烟和饮酒危害的宣传活动和广告一直坚持不懈。
For example, the Department of Transport's Think! campaign to raise awareness of the dangers of drink-driving, or the Department of Health's Change4Life campaign promoting the benefits of healthy food and exercise.
例如，交通部的“思考！”运动旨在提高人们对酒驾危害的认识，卫生部的“改变生活”运动则倡导健康饮食和锻炼的益处。
And while, for their predecessors, these behaviours may have become ingrained, it seems young people are taking these messages to heart.
虽然对前辈们来说，这些行为可能已经根深蒂固，但年轻人似乎把这些宣传理念牢记在心。
Another explanation could be based in youth's natural delinquency.
另一种解释可能与年轻人天生的叛逆性有关。
"Young people are rebelling against the older generations' chosen methods of rebellion," says Dr James Nicholls, Director of Research and Policy Development at Alcohol Research UK, speaking to the Guardian.
英国酒精研究中心研究与政策发展主任詹姆斯·尼科尔斯博士在接受《卫报》采访时表示：“年轻人正在反抗老一辈选择的叛逆方式。”
In other words, if the older generation's method of rebellion from their parents was to drink, smoke and act anti-socially, then their offspring's is to refrain.
换句话说，如果老一辈反抗父母的方式是喝酒、抽烟和做出反社会行为，那么他们的后代则选择克制这些行为来表示反抗。
Whether or not this will continue, only time will tell.
这种趋势是否会持续下去，只有时间能证明。
As these under-25s go through life, they may buck their current trend, and turn to the behaviour of their ancestors.
随着这些25岁以下的年轻人经历人生的不同阶段，他们可能会改变目前的趋势，转而效仿先辈们的行为。
However, they may stick to their guns and continue to be sensible.
不过，他们也可能坚持自己的做法，继续保持理智。
If this is indeed the case then a more interesting question arises. How will their youth react?
如果真是这样，一个更有趣的问题就会出现：他们的下一代会做出怎样的反应？